(飛段)チッ… ゼツかよ。
Zetsu, huh?
(ゼツ黒)どうやら
済んだようだな。
It appears it's done.
(ゼツ黒)長ったらしい儀式も
終わったか。
Finally finished with
your drawn-out ritual, huh?
あぁ どいつもコイツも
うるせえ野郎だ！
Nothing but annoying atheist jerks
who don't understand prayer!
祈りを知らねえ無神論者どもが！
(ゼツ白)悲しいときは 身ひとつ。
When you're sad and alone,
you can only trust in yourself.
(ゼツ黒)信じられるのは 己だけだ。
(角都)いや 違うな。
No, you're wrong.
信じられるのは カネだけだ。
(飛段)あぁ 出た それ！
You can only trust in money.
Oh, here we go!
お前の バイトのせいで➡
We've fallen behind with
our Jinchuriki hunt
人柱力探しが遅れてんだぜ。
だいたいよ…。
mostly because of your side job!
宗教は カネになると言ってきたから
お前と組んだんだ。
I teamed up with you because
you said religion is profitable.
暁の財布役を任されている
オレの身にもなれ。
I've been left in charge
of Akatsuki finances.
Put yourself in my shoes.
(ゼツ白)お金は大切だよね。
Money is important.
More importantly,
search for the next one immediately.
(ゼツ黒)そんなことより
すぐに 次を探索しろ。
二尾は オレが預かる。
I'll take charge of the Two-Tails.
(ヤマト)大丈夫なのかい？
昨日まで入院していたんだろ？
Are you sure you're okay?
You were in the hospital until
only yesterday, right?
(ナルト)あんなの
大げさにしすぎなんだって。
That was just blown
out of proportion!
(カカシ)おしゃべりは
そのくらいにして➡
That's enough talking.
Let's continue the training...
修業の続き… と
言いたいところだけど➡
That's what I'd like to say.
But first let's confirm the basics.
まず 基本の確認をしておこうか。
そんなのいいってばよ！
Forget about that!
早く オレに 新必殺技の
修業をつけてくれよ！
Let's hurry up and start the training
for my new knockout Jutsu!
The Super Ultra Deluxe Rasengan,
or the Special Naruto Uzumaki Rasengan,
超スーパーデラックス螺旋丸とか➡
ナルトスペシャル
うずまき螺旋丸とかさ！
or something like that!
(ヤマト)ハァ…。
だから そのための
チャクラの性質変化の修業でしょ。
That's what we're doing Change
in Chakra Nature training for, right?
火 風 水… 雷 土の
５種類の基本性質。
The five basic property types are fire,
wind, water, lightning and earth.
キミの場合は…。
オレは 風のチャクラ性質だ！
And in your case...
My Chakra property is wind!
じゃあ とりあえず 前に
やったとこまで やってみようか。
Then for the time being,
shall we go with what
we've done so far?
おう！ 多重影分身の術！
Right! Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
は～っ！
薄く 鋭くだってばよ！
Steady and sharp!
あぁ～！
We did it!
できた！
ど～んなもんだってばよ！
カカシ先生！
How about that, Kakashi Sensei?!
あ… あれ？
Huh?
(カカシ)まったく…。
Good grief.
病み上がりだってのに
ムチャしやがって。
He pushes it even though
he's still healing...
そもそも 多重影分身は
修業の効率を上げるための方法。
The Multi Shadow Clone is primarily used
as an approach for increasing
the effects of the training.
(ヤマト)修業の成果を見せるのには
必要ないでしょうに…。
It's not necessary for showing
the results of training.
(カカシ)ま ナルトらしいけどね。
Well, it is Naruto's style, though.
Akatsuki's Invasion
How deep into the mountains is it?
どんだけ山奥にあるんだよ…。
もうすぐだ。
We're almost there.
って ずっと そればっかじゃん。
You've been saying that
the whole time!
Come on. Give me a break!
We've got to climb again?!
(飛段)おいおい 勘弁しろよ。
また のぼりか？
これで 人柱力がいない
ってことになってみろよ。
What if it turns out
there's no Jinchuriki?!
I'll be really upset!
オレは キレるぜ！
I don't give a darn about you.
If you keep wailing like a little kid...
(角都)お前のことなど
知ったことか。
ガキみたいに
わめいていると… 殺すぞ。
I'll kill you.
だからよ
それを オレに言うかよ 角都。
Come on.
Don't give me that, Kakuzu!
Oh, man!
What an anti-social jerk.
(飛段)あぁ 無愛想な野郎だぜ。
(綱手)いくつかの
変更点はあるとしても➡
Even if there are several changes...
this would be the best plan
under the present conditions, huh?
現状で考えられる 最良の構成か。
(シズネ)はい。
Yes.
(綱手)２～３日のうちに
まとめあげ➡
Get everything compiled and
have it ready to transmit
in two or three days.
伝達できるよう 頼む。
(シズネ)わかりました。
Understood.
《苦労かけて すまんな。
Sorry to cause you trouble...
But we can't just sit around
doing nothing.
だが ちんたらして
いられそうもないのでな…》
(カカシ)目が覚めたか？
Are you awake?
あれ？ オレってば また…。
Huh...?
Again... I...
(カカシ)まだ寝てろ。
You keep resting.
多重影分身を使った修業方法は
疲れも たまりやすいからな。
Fatigue tends to build up
when using the Multi Shadow Clones
training approach.
(カカシ)もう少し休んでから
修業を始めよう。
Let's start the training again
after you've rested a little while.
次は 何するんだ？
What're we going to do next?
次か？ 次のステップは…。
Next?
The next step is...
(カカシ)滝を切る。
to cut that waterfall!
Put your hands on the waterfall
and cut it
滝に手をつけて 風のチャクラを
思いっきりぶつけて 切るんだ。
by hammering it
with your Wind Chakra.
切るって 滝を？
Cut...the waterfall?
瞬時に 多量の
性質変化を起こす訓練だよ。
For this training,
you need to instantly create
a Change in Chakra Nature
in a large amount of Chakra.
そうしないと
滝なんて切れないからね。
Or else you won't be able
to cut the waterfall.
(カカシ)この段階をクリアできれば➡
You'll more or less be able
to use it in real battle
if you can pass this stage of training.
とりあえず 実戦で使えるからな。
カカシ先生 それができりゃ➡
Kakashi Sensei!
If I can do that,
it means I have learned
my first Change in Chakra Nature, right?
オレもまず 一つの性質変化は
できたってことか？
All right, I'm getting better!
ようし オレ 成長してるってばよ！
《カカシ : あの不器用なナルトが➡
I never thought that clumsy Naruto
ここまで早く 性質変化を
起こせるようになるとは➡
would be able to create
a Change in Chakra Nature so soon.
思ってもみなかった。
この修業方法 大正解だったな》
This training approach...
was a big success.
Break time is over!
休憩終わり！
Let's get right back to training!
さっさと 修業再開だってばよ！
Wood Style Jutsu!
(ヤマト)木遁の術！
(カカシ)あそこが今度の 修業場だ。
That will be your training area.
Right.
うん！
(カカシ)でも ちょい待ち。
But hold on!
Whoa... What is it?
なんだってばよ!?
この修業は常に➡
You'll need Yamato's Chakra control
at all times during this training.
ヤマトの チャクラコントロールが必要だって
言ってるでしょ。
頼んだよ ヤマト。
はい。
I'm counting on you, Yamato.
Okay.
(ヤマト)ハッ！
STABILIZE
Preparations complete, Naruto!
準備完了だよ ナルト。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
《風のチャクラをイメージして…》
Form a mental image
of my Wind Chakra and...
Listen up. The Wind Change
in Chakra Nature...
((アスマ : いいか？ 風の性質変化は
チャクラを２つに分割して➡
splits Chakra in two and
grinds them together.
すり合わせるイメージだ。
すり合わせる？
Grinds them together?
そして ２つのチャクラを 互いに
薄く研ぐような感じで練り込め。
And then you build up the two Chakra
as if steadily sharpening them.
薄く 鋭く… 研ぐような感じか。
As if steadily...sharpening them...
(そうだ コツは より薄く 鋭くだ))
That's right...
The trick is steadier...and sharper.
薄く… 鋭くだ！
Steady and sharp!
Let's go, guys!
みんな いくぞ！
おぉ！
Right!
ハッ！
クッソ～！ 水が ちょいハネる程度か。
Damn it! The water should
splash just a bit...
次いくぞ！ 次！
おうよ！
Let's go to the next one!
Right!
ハッ！
As to be expected,
this will probably take a while.
(ヤマト)これは さすがに
時間が かかりそうですね。
Well, be patient.
まっ 気長にね。
ハッ！ ハッ！
(サクラ)材料は これでよしっと。
That should be it for the ingredients...
これで サクラ特製 スペシャル兵糧丸を
作ってあげられる。
Now I can make him some of
my special Sakura Food Pills!
《サクラ : アイツ きっとムリして➡
I'm sure he'll force himself
into doing more reckless training.
ムチャな修業するに
違いないんだから》
Geez...
《ったく 今どき流行らないわよ
根性で強くなるなんて。
Getting stronger with determination
just isn't done anymore.
ムリな修業は 体に負担を
かけるだけじゃなくて➡
Not only does excessive training
take a toll on the body,
逆効果になることだってある。
but it could also have
a reverse effect.
ましてや アイツは 人一倍
がんばることができる 特異体質》
Not only that, he also has
the physical idiosyncrasy
that allows him to work much harder
than other people.
That's right! The least I can do
is to help him any way I can.
《サクラ : そうよ せめて
私のできることで➡
力になってあげなきゃ》
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
ハァ～！ ハッ！
Damn it!
チクショウ！ クッソ～！
Damn...
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
He'll probably start getting
impatient pretty soon.
そろそろ じれ出す頃かな。
This is a temple.
Is there a Jinchuriki in a place like this?
(飛段)寺じゃねえかよ。
こんなところにいんのかよ？
Who knows?
(角都)さあな。 だが
ただの寺ではないからな➡
But this isn't an ordinary temple,
so there's a good possibility.
可能性は高い。
What was that?!
何事だ!?
封印鉄壁を 破った者がおる！
Someone destroyed the Iron Wall Seal!
地陸様に報告しろ！
Report this to Lord Chiriku!
(飛段)ジャシン教には➡
It doesn't look like these guys
want to convert to the Jashin religion.
改宗してくれそうにねえ
ツラしてんな どいつもコイツも。
None of these guys do...
あの衣… 今ウワサの！
That cloak... It's the rumored...
No doubt about it! It's the Akatsuki!
間違いない 暁だ！
We have intruders!
侵入者です！
(地陸)何者だ？
Who are they?
暁の手の者でございます！
They are with the Akatsuki!
《地陸 : いつか来るとは
思っていたが…》
I knew they'd come here eventually, but...
わしが出る。
他の者は 援護しろ。
I'll go!
Everyone else provide backup.
(飛段)あ？ また徳の高そうなのが
出てきたぜ。
Looks like we've got another
virtuous looking one...
He's not just virtuous.
(角都)徳だけではない。
He's got a 30 million ryo bounty
on his head in our Bingo Book.
こちら側のビンゴブックでは
3,000万両の賞金首だ。
(飛段)ハッ… おい 金儲けが
狙いじゃねえだろうな？
Hey...
You're not after money, are you?
そんなんで坊主やると
地獄へ落ちるぜ。
You'll go to hell if you kill
a monk for something like that.
Money is the key that opens all doors.
That's just what I want.
地獄の沙汰も カネ次第だ。
望むところ。
(地陸)貴殿ら 何用かは知らぬが
おとなしく帰られよ。
I don't know what you guys want.
But please leave quietly.
無益な殺生は しねえってか？
No meaningless slaughter, huh?
だが こっちの宗派じゃ
そうはいかねえ。
But it doesn't work like that
in my religion.
火ノ国に火ノ寺ありと
謳われた忍寺だ。
The Temple of Fire is the greatest
Shinobi temple in the Land of Fire.
僧侶は みな
仙族の才と呼ばれる特別な力を➡
And it is said that all of the monks
control the special power
known as the Gift of the Sages.
操ると言われている。
(角都)特に あの 3,000万両は➡
And the 30 million-ryo man is a Ninja
火ノ国の大名を守る
守護忍十二士にも➡
who was once chosen as a member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
who protected the Feudal Lord
of the Land of Fire.
選ばれたこともある エリート忍者だ。
あの火ノ国の紋が入った
腰布が その証し。
And the proof is that breechcloth
with the Land of Fire emblem on it...
へぇ それって すげえの？
No kidding?
Is he that incredible?
Don't get careless.
You'll die.
(角都)気を抜くな… 死ぬぞ。
Don't give me that...
だから オレに それを言うかよ！
(飛段)角都！
Kakuzu!
何だ あれは!?
What's that?!
I don't care.
Let's keep going.
かまわねえ このまま突っ込むぜ。
(飛段)もらった！
You're mine!
- Oh.
- Lord Chiriku won!
葬儀は出してやる。
I'll give you a funeral.
(飛段)誰が…
異教の葬儀なんか受けるかよ。
Who would accept
a different religion's funeral?
ジャシン様のバチが当たるぜ。
I'd receive divine retribution
from Lord Jashin...
頭きた… おい
コイツは人柱力じゃねえんだろ。
Now I'm mad...
Hey...
If this guy isn't a Jinchuriki...
なら オレの戒律
守っていいんだよな。
I can defend my commandments, right?
(角都)好きにしろ。
だが コイツの死体は カネになる。
Do as you like.
But his body is worth money.
(角都)誰だか わかるように
ほどほどにしとけよ。
Don't go overboard...
Make sure he's recognizable.
命を カネに換えるなんざ➡
Exchanging life for money
isn't something for people to do...
人のやることじゃねえぜ
…ったくよ！
Good grief.
(飛段)角都 手を出すなよ！
Kakuzu! Stay out of this!
コイツは オレが… やる！
I'll take care of...this guy!
火ノ寺の地陸。
Chiriku of the Temple of Fire will
not lose to wicked men like you!
キサマらごとき外道には
負けはせん！
Raikei!
来迎 千手殺！
Thousand Hand Strike!
(飛段)ぐぉ～!!
どうやら ここには
人柱力は いなかったみてえだな。
It appears there was no Jinchuriki here.
祈りが終わりしだい
次へ行こうぜ。
Let's move on to the next one as soon
as I'm done with my prayer.
(角都)イヤ…
コイツの死体を換金所に持って行く。
No...
I'm taking this body to trade in for money.
まずは金だ。
Money comes first.
あのさ！ オレ お前に１回
キレてもいいかな!? ホント！
Listen, you're really starting
to irritate me. Really...
《木ノ葉へ知らせなければ！》
I've got to inform the Hidden Leaf...
(飛段)だったら
とっとと行こうぜ。
Then let's get going.
火ノ国は広い… じっくり行くぞ。
The Land of Fire is huge.
Let's take our time.
やっぱ いろいろと出遅れてんのは
テメエのせいだろ！ クーッ いてえ！
I knew we were falling behind
because of you.
Ow!
待てや！ こら!!
Wait! Hey!
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
これじゃ 影分身が
少なすぎるんじゃねえの!?
Don't you think I need
more Shadow Clones?!
(カカシ)大量のチャクラを風に
性質変化させなきゃ滝は切れない。
You can't cut the waterfall
unless you perform
the Change in Chakra Nature
on a large amount of wind Chakra!
人数が多すぎれば 一人ひとりの
チャクラが分散しちまう。
The Chakra for each clone will disperse
if there are too many of them!
それに その滝の幅じゃ
10人並ぶのが やっとだ。
And we can barely line up ten clones
with the width of that waterfall!
え～！ なんだよそれ…。
Do you really want me
to learn this or not
だったら
ちょっとぐらい うまくなるコツ➡
Then tell us the trick to get just
a little bit better!
教えてくれってばよ！
(カカシ)作ったチャクラを
体内に溜める時間が短すぎる。
You're not holding the Chakra
you've built up inside
your body long enough!
もっと時間をかけて丁寧にやれ。
Take your time and be more efficient!
でも チンタラやってたら
実戦で役に立たねえじゃん！
But if we don't get a move on,
this won't be of any use in a real battle.
今は修業中だ。
実戦のことまで考えなくていい。
You're in training right now.
You don't need to be thinking
about real battles.
慣れれば早くなる。
でも…！
It will get quicker
once you get used to it.
あのね… 性質変化は
本来 何年もかかる修業なの。
葉を切るのだって
ホントなら半年はかかる。
(ヤマト)それを たった数時間で
クリアしたんだ。 焦ることないよ。
予想より何倍も早く進んでる。
(カカシ)天才肌のサスケでさえ
千鳥を教えたとき➡
雷の性質変化には
かなりの日数がかかった。
オレは そのサスケに
追いつかなきゃなんねえんだ！
(カカシ)…ったく。
(カカシ)テンゾウ。
わかりました。
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
さすがに きついか？
まったく…。
全然…。
《きついんだな…》
(カカシ)どうだ ナルト？
これで文句ないだろ？
ヘヘヘヘ… 多重影分身の術！
ハッ！
よい子のみんな 元気かな？
今日 みんなと一緒に挑戦するのは
この術！
火遁豪火球の術だ。
(子供たち)火遁豪火球？
(カカシ)そう！ 火遁豪火球とは
うちは一族に伝わる基本忍術。
体内で練ったチャクラを炎に変えて
火の球を口から吐き出す➡
サスケの得意技だ。
発動のために必要な印は
次の６つ。
(カカシ)午の印はちょっと難しいから
練習が必要かな。
すばやく印を結びながら
体内で チャクラを練り上げて➡
ノドのあたりに一度 溜めてから
一気に吐き出す！
それじゃあ
みんなで やってみよう！
(カカシ)チャクラを練ったら溜めて～
一気に吐く！
あのサスケだって はじめから
うまくできたわけじゃない！
何事も修業あるのみ！
それじゃあ またね！ バイバーイ！